CJ WILLIAMS

MARKETING DIRECTOR & UX/UI DESIGNER



Phone 406.579.1985



Email

cj@silencekillsdesign.com



Website

hirecj.netlify.com

SOCIAL



Twitter@s1lencek1lls



Facebook /cjwilliamsissilence



LinkedIn/cjwilliamsworks

EDUCATION

Treehouse Academy

Front-End Development Techdegree teamtreehouse.com 2014 - 2022

Montana State University

*Graphic Design & Music Technology*Bozeman, MT
2003 - 2008

SKILLS

- UX / UI DESIGN
- ADOBE CREATIVE CLOUD
- MICROSOFT OFFICE
- SEMRUSH
- HTML / CSS / IS
- VUE.JS / NUXT / VUEX
- TECHNICAL SEO / SEM / PPC
- WORDPRESS / WOOCOMMERCE

CERTIFICATIONS

- GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- ADVANCED GOOGLE ANALYTICS
- HUBSPOT INBOUND
- MOZ SEO TRAINING

PROFILE

Hey! Im CJ, a Marketing Director, UX and Systems Designer, and Front-End Web Developer with over 10 years of management experience. Scrappy and ambitious bootstrapper who wears many hats and loves learning. Accountable leader who lives in the trenches with the team. Data-driven decision maker, always aiming to optimize. Self-aware and open-minded jokester strapped with bad dad jokes aplenty. Admirer of driven peers, hard work, and frequently communicate appreciation on jobs well done. I've sometimes bitten off more than I can chew, but have gotten much better at delegation in the agile workflow.

EXPERIENCE

Hoists.com (and sister companies: Sievert Electric, Sievert Crane, and CES) Marketing and E-Commerce Director / February 2021 - Present

- Architected a growing dynamic product catalog for multiple brands and product configurations with forethought of ERP and API integration strategy
- Successfully launched Hoists.com with an average of 2.4k visitors/mo. with a performant ad budget averaging \$0.35/click over its first quarter
- Led a lean department coordinated with independent contractors on goals
- Optimized inherited Ads campaign, reducing CPC by 80% and budger by 73%, while increasing clicks by 37% and impressions by 738%
- · Multi-site web development and cross-platform tracking
- Technical SEO, SEM, SMM, and PPC strategy and management
- Created targeted email marketing strategy and execution to segmented lists
- Lead infrastructure development for Customer & Communications Support
- Audio / Video / Digital asset production and placement

SilenceKillsDesign

Ageny Owner / 2007 - 2021

- UX Research and Development for multi-million dollar national B2B clientelle
- Managed multiple clients' online presence from conception to completion
- Designed SaaS admin interfaces for web apps for integration with Oracle
- Brand asset design for digital and print mediums
- Website and e-commerce development, design, and optimization
- · Persona Reserach and Development
- Owned SEO / SEM / PPC / SMM strategies, tracking, and reporting
- Track and report on KPI and goal completion in Google Analytics

Xtant Medical (formerly Bacterin International) Digital Marketing Manager / 2012 - 2016

- · Led design and digital strategy when Xtant Medical acquired became
- Developed public-facing site and constant A/B testing
- Developed investor and internal sales portals for access to private information
- Location-based campaign strategies around tradeshows and events
- · B2B and Internal Email campaign management and tracking
- Adherence to ISO 13485:2003 quality standards and internal SOP
- · Ad buying, event planning, and tradeshow coordination with sales team